<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <color name="black">#FF000000</color>
    <color name="white">#FFFFFFFF</color>
    <string name="app_name">projet m2</string>
    <string name="cours1">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 1: Introduction to Algorithms</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Introduction</b></font><br> Programming can seem hard at first. Before writing any code, we need to learn how to think like a computer. That’s where algorithms come in.<br> An algorithm is just a step-by-step plan to solve a problem. Think of it like a recipe: it tells you exactly what to do, in which order, to get the result you want.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. What is an Algorithm?</b></font><br> An algorithm is a list of instructions to solve a problem or complete a task.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>Example 1: Making a cup of coffee</b></font><br> 1. Boil water<br> 2. Put coffee in a cup<br> 3. Pour hot water into the cup<br> 4. Stir<br> 5. Enjoy your coffee<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>Example 2: Finding the average of three numbers</b></font><br> 1. Add the three numbers<br> 2. Divide the result by 3<br> 3. Show the answer<br><br> A good algorithm must be:<br> - Clear: Each step is easy to understand.<br> - Finite: It must finish after a limited number of steps.<br> - Efficient: It should not waste time or resources.<br> - Correct: It must give the right result for all valid inputs.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Structure of an Algorithm</b></font><br> Every algorithm has three main parts:<br><br> 1. Input: The data you start with.<br> Example: Three numbers to calculate the average.<br><br> 2. Processing: The steps to solve the problem.<br> Example: Add the numbers and divide by three.<br><br> 3. Output: The result of the algorithm.<br> Example: The average of the three numbers.<br><br> Simple template:<br> Start<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Read the input<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Do the calculations<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Show the result<br> End<br><br> Remember: This structure works for small problems (like adding numbers) and big problems (like sorting thousands of names). ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours10">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 10: REPEAT Loop (Repeat Until a Condition Becomes True)</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is a REPEAT Loop?</b></font><br> A REPEAT loop (also known as DO…UNTIL) repeats actions at least once, and continues until a condition becomes true.<br><br> Difference with WHILE:<br> - WHILE checks the condition before the loop<br> - REPEAT checks the condition after running the steps<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. How It Works</b></font><br> - Do the actions<br> - Check if the condition is true<br> - If not, repeat again<br> The loop always runs at least one time.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Structure (in natural language)</b></font><br> REPEAT<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Do this action<br> UNTIL condition becomes true<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Examples</b></font><br> - “REPEAT read password UNTIL password == correct_password.” → The user must try at least once<br> - “REPEAT decrease temperature UNTIL temperature == 0.”<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Why Use REPEAT Loops?</b></font><br> Use REPEAT when:<br> - The actions must happen at least once<br> - You want to check the condition at the end<br> - The loop depends on reaching a final state<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours10_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 10: FOR Loop (Repeating Actions a Fixed Number of Times)</b></font><br><br> A loop allows you to repeat instructions automatically.<br> The FOR loop repeats actions a specific number of times.<br><br> Use it when:<br><br> - You know how many times the loop must run<br> - You need to go through numbers (e.g. 1 to 10)<br> - You process arrays or series<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Basic Structure</b></font><br><br> for (start; condition; step) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;// instructions<br> }<br><br> Meaning:<br> start → initialize a counter variable<br> condition → loop continues as long as this is true<br> step → change the counter (usually +1)<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Simple Example (Counting)</b></font><br><br> for (int i = 1; i &lt;= 5; i++) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("%d\n", i);<br> }<br><br> Output:<br> 1<br> 2<br> 3<br> 4<br> 5<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Example: Print "Hello" 3 Times</b></font><br><br> for (int i = 0; i &lt; 3; i++) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Hello\n");<br> }<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Example With Calculations</b></font><br><br> int sum = 0;<br><br> for (int i = 1; i &lt;= 5; i++) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;sum = sum + i;<br> }<br><br> printf("Sum = %d", sum);<br><br> This calculates: 1 + 2 + 3 + 4 + 5<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. How the FOR Loop Works Internally</b></font><br><br> For the loop:<br> for (int i = 0; i &lt; 3; i++)<br><br> Steps:<br> start → i = 0<br> condition → is i &lt; 3 ? Yes<br> run code inside<br> step → i++ (i becomes 1)<br> repeat<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>6. Summary</b></font><br><br> The FOR loop is perfect when you know:<br> - where the loop starts<br> - where it ends<br> - how it increases<br><br> It is used for:<br> - counting<br> - repeating actions<br> - working with arrays<br> - creating tables or sequences<br><br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours11">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 11: Arrays (TAB)</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is an Array?</b></font><br> An array (or TAB) is a structure that stores multiple values inside a single variable.<br> It is like a row of boxes, each one holding a value.<br><br> Example in real life:<br> - A list of student names<br> - A series of daily temperatures<br> - A collection of scores in a game<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Why Use Arrays?</b></font><br> Arrays allow the algorithm to:<br> - Store many values of the same type<br> - Access values easily using positions (indexes)<br> - Organize data more efficiently<br> - Avoid creating many separate variables<br><br> Instead of:<br> score1, score2, score3, score4<br> You use:<br> score[1], score[2], score[3], score[4]<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Structure of an Array</b></font><br> An array has:<br> - A name<br> - A size (number of elements)<br> - A type (all elements share the same type)<br><br> Example:<br> “Create an array called grades with 5 integers.”<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Accessing Elements</b></font><br> Elements are accessed using an index (a position number).<br><br> Example:<br> - grades[1] → first element<br> - grades[5] → fifth element<br><br> Indexes help the algorithm find the correct value quickly.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Simple Example</b></font><br> Goal: Read 3 temperatures and display them.<br> Steps:<br> - READ temperature[1]<br> - READ temperature[2]<br> - READ temperature[3]<br> - WRITE all temperature values<br><br> The array stores all the values in one place.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>6. Why Arrays Are Important</b></font><br> Arrays are essential for:<br> - Handling lists<br> - Storing repeated information<br> - Working with loops<br> - Managing data structures (matrices, lists, etc.)<br><br> They are a key building block in algorithmics and programming.<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours11_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 11: WHILE Loop (Repeat as Long as a Condition Is True)</b></font><br><br> The WHILE loop is used when you want to repeat instructions as long as a condition is true.<br> Unlike the FOR loop, you don’t need to know how many times it will repeat.<br><br> Use WHILE when:<br><br> - the number of repetitions is unknown<br> - the loop depends on a condition<br> - you wait for something to happen (ex: user enters correct number)<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Basic Structure</b></font><br><br> while (condition) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;// instructions<br> }<br><br> The loop runs only if the condition is true.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Simple Example: Count from 1 to 5</b></font><br><br> int i = 1;<br><br> while (i &lt;= 5) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("%d\\n", i);<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;i++; // update the counter<br> }<br><br> The condition i &lt;= 5 keeps the loop running.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Example: Ask Until User Enters a Positive Number</b></font><br><br> int number = -1;<br><br> while (number &lt; 0) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Enter a positive number: ");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;scanf("%d", &number);<br> }<br><br> The loop stops once the user enters a positive number.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Important: Avoid Infinite Loops</b></font><br><br> An infinite loop happens when the condition never becomes false.<br><br> Example of a mistake:<br><br> int i = 0;<br><br> while (i &lt; 3) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Hello");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;// missing i++<br> }<br><br> Always make sure the variable inside the condition changes.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Summary</b></font><br><br> WHILE repeats as long as the condition is true<br> Good for loops where you don’t know the number of repetitions<br> Condition must eventually become false<br> Used a lot with user input<br><br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours12">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 12: Pointers (Introduction Only)</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is a Pointer?</b></font><br> A pointer is a special type of variable that does not store a value directly.<br> Instead, it stores the address (the location) of another variable in memory.<br><br> Think of it like:<br> - A sign that points to a box<br> - It doesn’t contain the object, but it tells you where it is<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Why Use Pointers?</b></font><br> Pointers allow algorithms and programs to:<br> - Access and modify values indirectly<br> - Share information between different parts of a program<br> - Save memory<br> - Work with dynamic data structures (lists, trees, etc.)<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Basic Idea (in simple words)</b></font><br> If we have:<br> - A variable: age = 20<br> - A pointer: p that points to age<br><br> Then:<br> - The pointer does not store 20<br> - It stores “the place where age is located”<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Simple Example (concept only)</b></font><br> - “Let p point to the variable score.”<br> - “If we change the value through p, score also changes.”<br><br> Pointers are powerful but must be used carefully.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Why Teach Pointers?</b></font><br> Because they are essential to understand:<br> - Memory<br> - Dynamic structures<br> - Linked lists<br> - Some advanced algorithms<br><br> This lesson is only a simple introduction.<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours12_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 12: DO…WHILE Loop (Repeat At Least Once)</b></font><br><br> The DO…WHILE loop is similar to the WHILE loop, but with an important difference:<br><br> The instructions run at least once, even if the condition is false.<br> This is because the condition is checked after the loop body.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Basic Structure</b></font><br><br> do {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;// instructions<br> } while (condition);<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Example: Ask for a Number at Least Once</b></font><br><br> int number;<br><br> do {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Enter a number greater than 0: ");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;scanf("%d", &number);<br> } while (number &lt;= 0);<br><br> Even if the user enters a wrong number first, the loop ensures the question is asked again.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Example: Display a Menu Until User Chooses "0"</b></font><br><br> int choice;<br><br> do {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("1. Play\\n");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("2. Options\\n");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("0. Exit\\n");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;scanf("%d", &choice);<br> } while (choice != 0);<br><br> The menu appears at least once, guaranteed.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. When to Use DO…WHILE</b></font><br><br> Use it when:<br> - you want the loop to run at least once<br> - you check the condition after the code<br> - common in menus, validation, retry logic<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Summary</b></font><br><br> DO…WHILE runs the code first, then checks the condition<br> Guarantees that the instructions execute at least once<br> Useful for menus and user input validation<br><br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours13">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 13: Records / Structures (Enregistrements)</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is a Record?</b></font><br> A record (also called a structure) is a type of data that groups several pieces of information together.<br> It is like a custom container that stores different fields.<br><br> Example in real life:<br> - A student profile<br> - A product in a store<br> - A contact in a phone book<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Why Use Records?</b></font><br> Records allow algorithms to:<br> - Combine different data types in one object<br> - Keep related information together<br> - Make data easier to manage<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Structure of a Record</b></font><br> A record has:<br> - A name<br> - Several fields, each with its own data type<br><br> Example (in simple words):<br> Student Record:<br> - name → String<br> - age → Integer<br> - grade → Real<br><br> This groups all student information in one variable.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Simple Example</b></font><br> Imagine we want to store information about a book.<br> Record: Book<br> - title → String<br> - author → String<br> - pages → Integer<br><br> Now the algorithm can work easily with one object: Book.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Why Records Are Important</b></font><br> Records help to:<br> - Organize complex data<br> - Avoid many separate variables<br> - Build advanced data types<br> - Prepare for object-oriented programming<br><br> They are widely used in real applications.<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours13_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 13: Arrays (TAB)</b></font><br><br> An array is a structure that lets you store multiple values of the same type in a single variable.<br> Think of an array like a row of boxes, each box storing one value.<br><br> Example:<br> A variable stores one number.<br> An array can store many numbers.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Why Use Arrays?</b></font><br><br> Without an array:<br> int a, b, c, d, e; // Hard to manage<br><br> With an array:<br> int numbers[5]; // Stores 5 integers<br><br> More organized, easier to use, easier to repeat operations.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Declaring an Array</b></font><br><br> type name[size];<br><br> Examples:<br> int notes[10]; // 10 integers<br> float prices[4]; // 4 decimal numbers<br> char letters[26]; // 26 characters<br><br> The size must be known in advance.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Accessing Elements</b></font><br><br> Each position has a number called an index.<br> Indexes start at 0.<br><br> Example:<br> Index: 0 1 2 3 4<br> Value: [ ] [ ] [ ] [ ] [ ]<br><br> To access an element:<br> notes[0] = 15; // first element<br> notes[1] = 12; // second element<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Initializing an Array</b></font><br><br> Method 1: Manual<br> int numbers[3] = {10, 20, 30};<br><br> Method 2: Empty values<br> int numbers[5] = {0};<br><br> Method 3: Let the compiler count<br> int numbers[] = {3, 6, 9, 12};<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Using Arrays in Loops</b></font><br><br> The FOR loop is perfect to fill or read an array.<br><br> Example: Enter 5 numbers from the user<br> int tab[5];<br><br> for (int i = 0; i &lt; 5; i++) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;scanf("%d", &tab[i]);<br> }<br><br> Example: Display the numbers<br> for (int i = 0; i &lt; 5; i++) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("%d ", tab[i]);<br> }<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>6. Common Mistakes</b></font><br><br> ❌ Accessing outside the array size:<br> tab[5] = 10; // WRONG (index goes from 0 to 4)<br><br> ❌ Negative index:<br> tab[-1] = 2; // WRONG<br><br> ❌ forgetting the size:<br> int tab[]; // WRONG<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>7. Summary</b></font><br><br> Arrays store multiple values of the same type<br> Index starts at 0<br> Always respect the array size<br> Used in loops for reading or displaying data<br> Very useful for data processing<br><br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours14">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 14: Lists (Linked Lists — Simple Introduction)</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is a List?</b></font><br> A list is a dynamic data structure made of several elements, each one connected to the next.<br><br> Each element contains:<br> - A value<br> - A pointer to the next element<br><br> This is called a linked list.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. How Does a List Work?</b></font><br> A list starts with a special element called the head.<br> Each element points to the next, forming a chain.<br><br> Example:<br> [Value1] → [Value2] → [Value3] → NULL<br> “NULL” means the end of the list.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Why Use Lists?</b></font><br> Lists are useful because they:<br> - Grow and shrink easily<br> - Do not need a fixed size (unlike arrays)<br> - Are efficient for inserting or removing elements<br> - Are the base of many advanced structures<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Basic Operations on Lists</b></font><br> Even beginners can understand the main actions:<br> - Create a list<br> - Add an element<br> - Remove an element<br> - Read all elements by following each pointer<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Simple Example (concept only)</b></font><br> Imagine storing student names in a list:<br> - 1st element → "Alice"<br> - 2nd element → "Mark"<br> - 3rd element → "Sara"<br><br> Each element points to the next.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>6. Why Lists Matter</b></font><br> Linked lists are the foundation of:<br> - Stacks<br> - Queues<br> - Trees<br> - Graphs<br><br> Learning them early helps understand more advanced algorithms later.<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours14_C">
<![CDATA[ <span style="color:#FF0000"><b>Course 14: Introduction to Pointers (Simple & Beginner Level)</b></span><br><br> A pointer is a special variable that stores the memory address of another variable.<br><br> Imagine:<br> A normal variable = a box containing a value<br> A pointer = a paper that contains the location of the box<br><br> <span style="color:#800080"><b>1. Why Do We Use Pointers?</b></span><br><br> Pointers help us:<br> - Access or modify variables from different parts of the program<br> - Share data between functions<br> - Work with arrays and strings<br> - Manage memory efficiently<br><br> For beginners, think of a pointer as a “reference” to a variable.<br><br> <span style="color:#800080"><b>2. Declaring a Pointer</b></span><br><br> A pointer is declared using *.<br> This means: p will store the address of an int.<br><br> <span style="color:#800080"><b>3. Getting the Address of a Variable</b></span><br><br> We use the &amp; operator:<br> int age = 20;<br> int *p = &amp;age;<br><br> <span style="color:#800080"><b>4. Accessing the Value Through a Pointer</b></span><br><br> We use * again:<br> printf("%d", *p);<br><br> <span style="color:#800080"><b>5. A Simple Complete Example</b></span><br><br> int age = 20;<br> int *p;<br> p = &amp;age;<br><br> printf("Value: %d\\n", age);<br> printf("Address: %p\\n", p);<br> printf("Value through pointer: %d\\n", *p);<br><br> <span style="color:#800080"><b>6. Summary</b></span><br><br> - A pointer stores a memory address<br> - &amp;var → address of a variable<br> - *p → value at the pointer’s address<br> - Essential for arrays, strings, and advanced programming<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours15">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 15: Subprograms — Procedures and Functions</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is a Subprogram?</b></font><br> A subprogram is a small part of an algorithm that performs a specific task.<br> Instead of writing the same steps multiple times, we place them in a subprogram and reuse them.<br><br> There are 2 types:<br> - Procedures → perform an action<br> - Functions → perform an action and return a value<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Why Use Subprograms?</b></font><br> Subprograms help to:<br> - Avoid repeating code<br> - Make algorithms easier to understand<br> - Divide a big problem into smaller pieces<br> - Reuse logic in multiple places<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Procedures (in natural language)</b></font><br> A procedure does something but does not return a value.<br><br> Example:<br> “Procedure ShowWelcomeMessage: WRITE ‘Welcome to the app!’.”<br> We call it like this:<br> “Call ShowWelcomeMessage.”<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Functions (in natural language)</b></font><br> A function returns a value.<br><br> Example:<br> “Function Add(a, b) returns a + b.”<br> Calling the function:<br> “Set result to Add(3, 5).”<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Real-Life Example</b></font><br> Imagine a calculator app:<br> - Procedure → “ClearScreen()”<br> - Function → “Multiply(x, y) returns x * y”<br><br> Functions compute results.<br> Procedures perform tasks.<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours15_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 15: Records / Structures (struct)</b></font><br><br> A structure (or record) is a group of variables combined together under a single name.<br><br> Example: A student has:<br> - a name<br> - an age<br> - a grade<br><br> These can be grouped inside one structure.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Why Use Structures?</b></font><br><br> Structures help us:<br> - Organize related data<br> - Group multiple types together<br> - Create custom data types<br><br> Without structures:<br> char name[20];<br> int age;<br> float grade;<br><br> With structures:<br> struct Student {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;char name[20];<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;int age;<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;float grade;<br> };<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Declaring a Structure</b></font><br><br> struct Student {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;char name[20];<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;int age;<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;float grade;<br> };<br><br> You create a new “type” called Student.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Creating a Variable of the Structure</b></font><br><br> struct Student s1;<br><br> This represents one student.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Accessing Structure Members</b></font><br><br> We use the dot ( . ) operator:<br><br> s1.age = 18;<br> s1.grade = 15.5;<br><br> To read values:<br> printf("%d", s1.age);<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Example with Input and Output</b></font><br><br> struct Student {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;char name[20];<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;int age;<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;float grade;<br> };<br><br> struct Student s1;<br><br> scanf("%s", s1.name);<br> scanf("%d", &s1.age);<br> scanf("%f", &s1.grade);<br><br> printf("Name: %s\\n", s1.name);<br> printf("Age: %d\\n", s1.age);<br> printf("Grade: %.2f\\n", s1.grade);<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>6. Summary</b></font><br><br> A structure groups different data types together<br> Access elements using the dot operator<br> Useful for organizing complex information<br> Essential for real projects (students, cars, books, products…)<br><br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours16">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 16: Problem-Solving Methodology (Pseudocode & Logic)</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Why Methodology Matters</b></font><br> Before writing an algorithm, beginners must learn how to think logically.<br> Good planning = clear, simple algorithms.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Steps to Solve a Problem</b></font><br> - Understand the problem<br> - What do we want?<br> - What are the inputs?<br> - What should the result be?<br> - Identify the data<br> - Variables needed<br> - Types of values<br> - Break the problem into steps<br> - Small, clear actions<br> - Logical order<br> - Write the pseudocode<br> - A simple description of the algorithm<br> - Not programming yet<br> - Test with small values<br> - Check if the algorithm works<br> - Correct errors<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. What Is Pseudocode?</b></font><br> Pseudocode is a way to write algorithms in human language.<br> It helps beginners focus on logic, not syntax.<br><br> Example:<br> READ number<br> IF number &gt; 0<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;WRITE "Positive"<br> ELSE<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;WRITE "Negative"<br> END IF<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Tips for Good Logic</b></font><br> - One action per line<br> - Use clear names for variables<br> - Keep steps simple and ordered<br> - Test with different cases<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours16_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 16: Linked Lists (Beginner Level)</b></font><br><br> A linked list is a structure used to store multiple elements, like an array.<br> BUT unlike an array, the elements are not stored next to each other in memory.<br><br> Each element contains:<br> - The value<br> - The address of the next element<br><br> This creates a chain of elements.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Why Use Linked Lists?</b></font><br><br> - The size can grow or shrink when needed<br> - No need to decide the size in advance<br> - Easy to insert or delete elements<br> - Unlike arrays, linked lists are flexible<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Structure of a Node</b></font><br><br> A linked list is made of nodes.<br><br> struct Node {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;int value;<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;struct Node *next; // pointer to the next node<br> };<br><br> Each node stores:<br> - an integer<br> - a pointer to the next node<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Creating the First Node</b></font><br><br> struct Node *head = NULL;<br><br> Here, the list is empty.<br> To create a new node:<br> struct Node *newNode = malloc(sizeof(struct Node));<br> newNode->value = 10;<br> newNode->next = NULL;<br><br> head = newNode;<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Adding a Node at the End</b></font><br><br> struct Node *newNode = malloc(sizeof(struct Node));<br> newNode->value = 20;<br> newNode->next = NULL;<br><br> head->next = newNode; // connect the chain<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Moving Through the List</b></font><br><br> struct Node *current = head;<br><br> while (current != NULL) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("%d ", current->value);<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;current = current->next;<br> }<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>6. Summary</b></font><br><br> - A linked list is a chain of nodes<br> - Each node contains a value and a pointer<br> - Size can grow dynamically<br> - Useful for flexible data structures<br><br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours17">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 17: Classic Algorithm Exercises</b></font><br><br> These exercises are essential for beginners because they teach logic and reasoning.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Finding the Maximum of Two Numbers</b></font><br> Steps (in words):<br> - READ a<br> - READ b<br> - IF a &gt; b → max = a<br> - ELSE → max = b<br> - WRITE max<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Calculating the Sum of N Numbers</b></font><br> Steps:<br> - READ n<br> - sum = 0<br> - FOR i from 1 to n<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;READ number<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;sum = sum + number<br> - WRITE sum<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Searching for a Value in a List</b></font><br> Steps:<br> - READ the list<br> - READ the target value<br> - FOR each element<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;IF element == target → FOUND<br> - IF nothing found → NOT FOUND<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Counting How Many Numbers Are Even</b></font><br> Steps:<br> - READ n<br> - count = 0<br> - FOR i from 1 to n<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;READ number<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;IF number % 2 == 0 → count = count + 1<br> - WRITE count<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours17_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 17: Functions and Procedures (Subprograms)</b></font><br><br> In C, a program can become long and difficult to manage.<br> To avoid repeating code, we divide the program into subprograms.<br><br> There are two types:<br> 1. Functions (return a value)<br> 2. Procedures (do not return a value, called “void” in C)<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is a Function?</b></font><br><br> A function performs an operation and returns a result.<br><br> Example:<br> int add(int a, int b) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;return a + b;<br> }<br><br> To use it:<br> int result = add(5, 3); // result = 8<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. What Is a Procedure? (void function)</b></font><br><br> A procedure performs an action but does not return a value.<br><br> void greet() {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Hello!");<br> }<br><br> Use it like this:<br> greet();<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Why Use Functions?</b></font><br><br> - Make the code more organized<br> - Reuse code easily<br> - Avoid repeating logic<br> - Easier to maintain a program<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Parameters</b></font><br><br> Functions can receive inputs called parameters.<br><br> void showAge(int age) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Age: %d", age);<br> }<br><br> <font color="#008000"><b>5. Summary</b></font><br><br> - Functions return values<br> - Procedures (void functions) do not<br> - Subprograms make programs clear and modular<br> - Parameters allow communication between parts of the program<br><br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours18">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 18: Simple Sorting Algorithms (Beginner Level)</b></font><br><br> Sorting means ordering data (from smallest to largest, for example).<br> Here are two simple sorting methods for beginners.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Bubble Sort (Simple but slow)</b></font><br> Idea:<br> Compare each pair of numbers and swap them if they are in the wrong order.<br> Repeat until the list is sorted.<br><br> Steps:<br> - FOR i from 1 to length<br> - &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;FOR j from 1 to length − i<br> - &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;IF list[j] &gt; list[j+1]<br> - &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Swap them<br><br> Bubble sort is easy to understand.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Selection Sort</b></font><br> Idea:<br> Each time, find the smallest element and put it in the correct position.<br><br> Steps:<br> - FOR i from 1 to length<br> - &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Find the smallest element in the remaining part<br> - &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Swap it with element at position i<br><br> Selection sort is simple and predictable.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Why Learn Sorting?</b></font><br> Sorting teaches beginners:<br> - How loops interact<br> - How comparisons work<br> - How data moves in memory<br> - Basic algorithm efficiency<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours1_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 1: Introduction to C</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is the C Programming Language?</b></font><br> C is a powerful and flexible programming language used to create software, operating systems, games, and more.<br> It is known for being:<br> - Fast<br> - Efficient<br> - Close to the hardware<br> - Great for learning programming basics<br><br> Many modern languages (like C++, Java, and Python) were influenced by C.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Why Learn C?</b></font><br> Learning C helps you:<br> - Understand how computers manage memory<br> - Build a strong foundation for other languages<br> - Write fast and optimized programs<br> - Develop good programming habits<br><br> C is often taught first because it gives beginners a clear understanding of how programs really work.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Where Is C Used?</b></font><br> C is used in many fields:<br> - Operating systems (Windows, Linux parts, Android)<br> - Embedded systems (microcontrollers, IoT)<br> - Game engines<br> - Compilers and interpreters<br> - High-performance applications<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. What Do You Need to Program in C?</b></font><br> To write and run C programs, you need:<br> - A text editor (VS Code, Notepad++, Code::Blocks, etc.)<br> - A C compiler. Common options:<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;• GCC<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;• Clang<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;• MinGW<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;• The compiler included in Code::Blocks or Dev-C++<br><br> The compiler transforms your code into a program your computer can run.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. What Does a Simple C Program Look Like?</b></font><br> Here is a tiny example:<br> <pre> #include &lt;stdio.h&gt; int main() { printf("Hello, C!"); return 0; } </pre> This program displays: Hello, C!<br> You don’t need to fully understand it yet — you will learn each part step by step in the next courses.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>6. What You Will Learn Next</b></font><br> In the upcoming lessons, you will learn:<br> - How to install and use a C compiler<br> - How a C program is structured<br> - How to declare variables<br> - How to use conditions, loops, arrays, functions, and more<br><br> By the end, you will be able to create small programs by yourself.<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours2">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course: Declaring Variables (Algorithmics)</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is a Variable?</b></font><br> A variable is a “container” that stores information while an algorithm is running.<br> You can imagine it like a small box where you keep a value (a number, a word, etc.).<br> This value can change during the execution of the algorithm — that is why we call it a variable.<br><br> Examples of real-life variables:<br> - The score in a game<br> - The temperature during the day<br> - Your age<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Why Do We Use Variables in Algorithms?</b></font><br> Variables help us:<br> - Save information<br> - Reuse values later<br> - Make algorithms flexible<br> - Avoid repeating the same number or text several times<br> - Perform calculations and store the results<br><br> Without variables, an algorithm could not “remember” anything.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Declaring a Variable</b></font><br> Before using a variable in an algorithm, we must declare it.<br> Declaring a variable means specifying:<br> 1. The name of the variable<br> 2. The type of value it will store<br><br> Examples:<br> - Create a variable called "age" that will store a number.<br> - Create a variable called "name" that will store text.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Common Variable Types</b></font><br> - <b>Integer</b> → whole numbers<br> - <b>Real</b> → decimals<br> - <b>Character</b> → one symbol<br> - <b>String</b> → text<br> - <b>Boolean</b> → true or false<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Assigning a Value</b></font><br> Examples:<br> - Set age to 18.<br> - Set temperature to 25.5.<br> - Set name to "Mark".<br><br> We can also change values later:<br> - Set age to age + 1.<br> - Set score to 0, then increase it.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>6. Example</b></font><br> Variables needed:<br> - number1<br> - number2<br> - sum<br><br> Steps:<br> 1. Ask the user for number1<br> 2. Ask the user for number2<br> 3. Set sum to number1 + number2<br> 4. Display sum<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>Conclusion</b></font><br> Variables are essential in algorithms. They allow storing, reusing, and modifying information. ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours2_C">
<![CDATA[ <b>Course 2: Installing and Using a C Compiler (Simple Explanation)</b><br><br> <b>1. What Is a Compiler?</b><br> When you write a C program, the computer cannot understand your text directly.<br> A compiler is a special tool that translates your code into a real program that the computer can run.<br><br> Think of it like this:<br> - You write instructions in C<br> - The compiler transforms them<br> - Your computer can finally execute the program<br><br> Without a compiler, your C code would be just a normal text file.<br><br> <b>2. Tools You Need to Start Programming in C</b><br> To begin writing C programs, you only need two tools:<br><br> 1. A text editor<br> A place where you can write your code.<br><br> 2. A compiler<br> The tool that converts your code into an executable program.<br><br> <b>3. The Easiest Way to Start: Code::Blocks</b><br> Install Code::Blocks with GCC included.<br><br> <b>4. Using an Online Compiler (No Installation Needed)</b><br> You can use websites such as OnlineGDB or Replit.<br><br> <b>5. How C Programs Are Executed</b><br> The compiler checks your code and generates an executable program.<br><br> <b>6. You Are Ready to Start Coding</b><br> You can now write and run your first C program.<br><br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours3">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course: Data Types (Algorithmics Basics)</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Are Data Types?</b></font><br> A data type tells the algorithm what kind of value a variable can store.<br> It helps the algorithm know:<br> - How the value should be stored<br> - What operations are possible<br> - How much space is needed<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Why Are Data Types Important?</b></font><br> Data types allow the algorithm to:<br> - Use data correctly<br> - Avoid mistakes<br> - Perform correct calculations<br> - Organize memory efficiently<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Common Data Types</b></font><br> <b>Integer</b> → whole numbers<br> <b>Real</b> → decimals<br> <b>Character</b> → one symbol<br> <b>String</b> → text<br> <b>Boolean</b> → true or false<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. How to Choose?</b></font><br> - Counting → Integer<br> - Temperature → Real<br> - User name → String<br> - One letter → Character<br> - True/false → Boolean<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours3_C">
<![CDATA[ <b>Course 3: Structure of a C Program</b><br><br> When you write a program in C, the computer needs your instructions to follow a specific structure.<br> Even complex programs always start with the same basic format.<br><br> Here is a simple example we will explain step by step:<br><br> <code>#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;<br><br> int main() {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Hello, world!");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;return 0;<br> }</code><br><br> <b>1. Libraries (Include Section)</b><br> At the top of the program, you usually include libraries.<br> A library is a set of ready-made tools your program can use.<br><br> Example:<br> <code>#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;</code><br><br> This library allows your program to:<br> - display text on the screen<br> - read user input<br><br> Think of it like importing a toolbox.<br><br> <b>2. The Main Function (Program Entry Point)</b><br> The <code>main</code> function is where your program begins running.<br><br> <code>int main() { ... }</code><br><br> When you start your program, the computer begins reading the instructions inside this function.<br> Every C program must have a <code>main</code> function.<br><br> <b>3. Instructions Inside main</b><br> Inside the <code>main</code> function, you write all the actions you want the program to perform.<br><br> Example:<br> <code>printf("Hello, world!");</code><br><br> This instruction displays text on the screen.<br> Every instruction ends with a semicolon (<code>;</code>) — it tells the computer “this instruction is finished”.<br><br> <b>4. Comments (Notes for You)</b><br> Comments allow you to explain your code.<br> They are ignored by the computer, but useful for you.<br><br> Example:<br> <code>// This line prints a message<br> printf("Hello, world!");</code><br><br> <b>5. Ending the Program</b><br> At the end of the <code>main</code> function, you return a value:<br><br> <code>return 0;</code><br><br> Returning 0 means the program ended correctly.<br> This is a tradition in C — no need to fully understand it yet.<br><br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours4">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 4: Operators (Arithmetic, Relational, Logical)</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is an Operator?</b></font><br> An operator is a symbol that tells the algorithm to perform an action or calculation.<br> Operators help the algorithm do math, compare values, and make decisions.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Arithmetic Operators</b></font><br> Arithmetic operators are used for mathematical operations.<br><br> <b>+ (Addition)</b> → 5 + 3 = 8<br> <b>- (Subtraction)</b> → 10 - 4 = 6<br> <b>* (Multiplication)</b> → 4 * 2 = 8<br> <b>/ (Division)</b> → 8 / 2 = 4<br> <b>% (Modulo)</b> → 10 % 3 = 1 (remainder)<br><br> Examples:<br> - Set sum to number1 + number2.<br> - Set priceAfterTax to price * 1.2.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Relational Operators</b></font><br> Relational operators compare two values and return true or false.<br><br> <b>></b> → Greater than (10 > 3 → true)<br> <b> < </b> → Less than (2 < 1 → false)<br> <b>>=</b> → Greater or equal (5 >= 5 → true)<br> <b>&lt;=</b> → Less or equal (3 &lt;= 7 → true)<br> <b>==</b> → Equal (4 == 4 → true)<br> <b>!=</b> → Not equal (6 != 2 → true)<br><br> Examples:<br> - Check if age > 18.<br> - Check if score == 100.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Logical Operators</b></font><br> Logical operators are used with true/false values.<br><br> <b>AND</b> → both conditions must be true<br> <b>OR</b> → at least one condition is true<br> <b>NOT</b> → reverses true/false<br><br> Examples:<br> - Check if age > 18 AND hasID = true.<br> - Check if temperature < 0 OR raining = true.<br> - NOT(isEmpty).<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Why Are Operators Important?</b></font><br> Operators allow algorithms to:<br> - Perform calculations<br> - Compare values<br> - Create decision-making logic<br> - Build conditions<br><br> They are essential in most algorithms. ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours4_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 4: Variables in C</b></font><br><br> In programming, a variable is a small container that stores information.<br> In C, variables allow your program to remember values while it is running.<br><br> You can store:<br><br> numbers<br> text<br> characters<br> true/false values<br><br> A variable can change during the program — that’s why it is called a variable.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Why Do We Use Variables?</b></font><br><br> Variables allow us to:<br><br> Store information<br> Reuse values<br> Do calculations<br> Read and save user input<br> Change values during program execution<br><br> Without variables, a program cannot remember anything.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Declaring a Variable in C</b></font><br><br> Before you use a variable, you must declare it.<br> Declaring means telling C two things:<br><br> The type (what kind of data it will store)<br> The name (how you refer to it)<br><br> Example:<br><br> int age;<br> float price;<br> char letter;<br><br> Here:<br><br> int is for whole numbers<br> float is for decimal numbers<br> char is for a single character<br><br> age, price, and letter are the names of the variables.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Assigning a Value</b></font><br><br> After declaration, you can put a value inside the variable.<br><br> Example:<br> age = 18;<br> price = 12.5;<br> letter = "A" ;<br><br> You can also declare and assign in one step:<br> int score = 0;<br><br> This creates a variable named score and sets its value to 0.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Changing a Variable</b></font><br><br> A variable’s value can change during the program.<br><br> Example:<br> score = score + 10;<br> age = age + 1;<br><br> The program updates the value based on the previous one.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Displaying a Variable</b></font><br><br> To show a variable on the screen, you use printf.<br><br> Example:<br> printf("Age: %d", age);<br><br> %d tells C that the variable is an integer.<br> (You will learn about format specifiers later.)<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>6. Simple Example Program</b></font><br><br> #include &lt;stdio.h&gt;<br><br> int main() {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;int age = 20;<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;float price = 15.99;<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Age: %d\n", age);<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Price: %.2f", price);<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;return 0;<br> }<br><br> This program:<br><br> creates two variables<br> stores values inside them<br> displays them on screen<br><br> A variable in C has:<br><br> a type (int, float, char…)<br> a name<br> a value<br><br> You can:<br><br> create (declare) a variable<br> assign it a value<br> change the value<br> use it to display or calculate information<br><br> Variables are one of the most important foundations of C programming.<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours5">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 5: Input and Output Instructions — READ / WRITE</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Are Input and Output Instructions?</b></font><br> Input and output instructions allow the algorithm to communicate with the user.<br><br> <b>READ</b> → the user gives information<br> <b>WRITE</b> → the algorithm displays information<br><br> These are algorithmic concepts, not programming code.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. The READ Instruction (Input)</b></font><br> The READ instruction asks the user to enter a value.<br><br> Examples:<br> - READ age → the user enters their age.<br> - READ number1 → the algorithm waits for input.<br><br> Use READ whenever the algorithm needs information to continue.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. The WRITE Instruction (Output)</b></font><br> The WRITE instruction displays information to the user.<br><br> Examples:<br> - WRITE age → shows the value of age.<br> - WRITE "Hello!" → displays a message.<br> - WRITE sum → shows the result of a calculation.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Simple Example: Sum of Two Numbers</b></font><br> 1. READ number1<br> 2. READ number2<br> 3. Set sum to number1 + number2<br> 4. WRITE sum<br><br> The user enters two numbers → the algorithm calculates → the result is shown.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Why Are READ and WRITE Important?</b></font><br> READ and WRITE allow interaction:<br> - The user provides input<br> - The algorithm processes it<br> - The result is displayed<br><br> Without input/output, an algorithm cannot communicate or be useful. ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours5_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 5: Data Types in C</b></font><br><br> In C, every variable must have a data type.<br> A data type tells the computer:<br><br> what kind of value the variable stores<br> how much memory it needs<br> what operations are allowed (calculations, text handling, etc.)<br><br> Choosing the correct data type is important because C is a strongly typed language — you cannot mix types freely without rules.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Integer Types (Whole Numbers)</b></font><br><br> Integer types store whole numbers, positive or negative.<br><br> Example:<br> int age = 20;<br><br> Examples of valid integers:<br> 0, 15, -8, 1200<br><br> Beginners mainly use:<br><br> int &rarr; standard integer<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Floating-Point Types (Decimal Numbers)</b></font><br><br> Used for numbers with decimals:<br><br> float price = 12.50;<br> double pi = 3.14159;<br><br> float &rarr; less precision, uses less memory<br> double &rarr; more precision, recommended for scientific calculations<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Character Type</b></font><br><br> Used to store a single character.<br><br> char letter = &apos;A&apos;;<br><br> Important:<br> characters use single quotes &rarr; &apos;a&apos;, &apos;7&apos;, &apos;?&apos;<br> Numbers inside quotes are characters, not integers.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Strings in C</b></font><br><br> C does not have a real string type like other languages.<br> Instead, a string is an array of characters ending with \\0.<br><br> Example:<br> char name[20] = "Alice";<br><br> This stores up to 19 visible characters + 1 invisible terminator.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Boolean Type (True / False)</b></font><br><br> C originally had no boolean type, but modern C supports:<br><br> #include &lt;stdbool.h&gt;<br> bool isActive = true;<br><br> Boolean values:<br> true<br> false<br><br> Useful for conditions and loops.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>6. Summary Table (Beginner Friendly)</b></font><br><br> Type&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Meaning&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Example<br> int&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Whole numbers&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;int age = 18;<br> float&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Decimal numbers&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;float price = 9.99;<br> double&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Precise decimals&nbsp;&nbsp;double pi = 3.14;<br> char&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;One character&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;char letter = &apos;B&apos;;<br> char[]&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Text / string&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;char name[20] = "Tom";<br> bool&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;True / false&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;bool ok = true;<br><br> <font color="#008000"><b>Summary</b></font><br><br> Data types in C define what kind of information a variable can store.<br><br> The main types for beginners are:<br><br> int &rarr; whole numbers<br> float / double &rarr; decimals<br> char &rarr; characters<br> char[] &rarr; text<br> bool &rarr; true/false<br><br> They are the foundation for almost everything you will do in C programs.<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours6">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 6: IF / ELSE (Decision Making)</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is a Condition?</b></font><br> A condition is a question that can only be answered with true or false.<br> Conditions help the algorithm make decisions.<br><br> Example:<br> “If it is raining, take an umbrella.”<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. What Is IF / ELSE?</b></font><br> The IF / ELSE structure allows the algorithm to choose between two actions:<br><br> IF the condition is true → do Action 1<br> ELSE → do Action 2<br><br> It is the basic way to control the flow of an algorithm.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Structure (in natural language)</b></font><br> IF condition<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Do this<br> ELSE<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Do something else<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Simple Examples</b></font><br> - IF age > 18, WRITE "Adult", ELSE WRITE "Minor".<br> - IF score == 100, WRITE "Perfect!", ELSE WRITE "Try again!".<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Why Do We Use IF / ELSE?</b></font><br> Algorithms often need to react differently depending on the situation.<br> IF / ELSE makes programs flexible, smart, and dynamic.<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours6_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 6: Operators in C (Arithmetic, Relational, Logical)</b></font><br><br> Operators are symbols that allow your program to calculate, compare, and make decisions.<br> They are essential because they make expressions possible inside your instructions.<br><br> In C, operators are grouped into three main categories for beginners:<br><br> Arithmetic operators → for calculations<br> Relational operators → for comparisons<br> Logical operators → for conditions and decisions<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Arithmetic Operators (Calculations)</b></font><br><br> Arithmetic operators are used with numbers (int, float, double).<br><br> Operator&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Meaning&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Example<br> +&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Addition&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;a + b<br> -&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Subtraction&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;a - b<br> *&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Multiplication&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;a * b<br> /&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Division&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;a / b<br> %&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Remainder (modulo)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;a % b<br><br> Example:<br><br> int a = 10;<br> int b = 3;<br><br> int sum = a + b; // 13<br> int rest = a % b; // 1<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Relational Operators (Comparison)</b></font><br><br> Relational operators compare two values and return true (1) or false (0).<br><br> Operator&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Meaning&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Example<br> ==&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;equal&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;a == b<br> !=&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;not equal&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;a != b<br> >&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;greater than&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;a > b<br> <&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;less than&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;a < b<br> >=&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;greater or equal&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;a >= b<br> <=&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;less or equal&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;a <= b<br><br> Example:<br><br> int age = 18;<br><br> if (age >= 18) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;// This condition is true<br> }<br><br> Relational operators are the foundation of IF / ELSE conditions.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Logical Operators (Combine Conditions)</b></font><br><br> Logical operators are used to combine or modify conditions.<br><br> Operator&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Meaning&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Example<br> &&&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;AND&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;x > 0 && x < 10<br> ||&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;OR&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;a == 3 || b == 5<br> !&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;NOT&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;!isActive<br><br> Example:<br><br> int score = 80;<br> int age2 = 15;<br><br> if (score > 70 && age2 < 18) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;// both conditions must be true<br> }<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Example Program Using Operators</b></font><br><br> #include &lt;stdio.h&gt;<br><br> int main() {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;int a = 5, b = 2;<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;int sum = a + b;<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;int isGreater = (a > b); // returns 1 (true)<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Sum: %d\n", sum);<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Is a greater than b? %d", isGreater);<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;return 0;<br> }<br><br> This program:<br><br> ✔ uses arithmetic operators<br> ✔ uses a relational operator<br> ✔ displays results<br><br> <font color="#008000"><b>Summary</b></font><br><br> Operators allow your program to:<br><br> ✔ calculate with arithmetic operators<br> ✔ compare values with relational operators<br> ✔ combine conditions with logical operators<br><br> You will use operators in almost every program you write in C, especially inside conditions and loops.<br><br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours7">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 7: SWITCH / CASE (Multiple Choices)</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is SWITCH / CASE?</b></font><br> SWITCH / CASE is used when the algorithm must choose one action among many options.<br> It is clearer and cleaner than using many IF statements in a row.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. How It Works</b></font><br> The algorithm checks the value of a variable and executes the matching CASE.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Structure (in natural language)</b></font><br> SWITCH variable<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;CASE value1 → do action 1<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;CASE value2 → do action 2<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;CASE value3 → do action 3<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;DEFAULT → do something if no case matches<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Example</b></font><br> SWITCH choice<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;CASE 1 → WRITE "Start game"<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;CASE 2 → WRITE "Settings"<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;CASE 3 → WRITE "Exit"<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;DEFAULT → WRITE "Invalid choice"<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Why Use SWITCH / CASE?</b></font><br> SWITCH / CASE makes algorithms:<br> - Easier to read<br> - Better organized<br> - More efficient when many options exist<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours7_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 7: Input & Output Instructions in C (printf & scanf)</b></font><br><br> In C, a program often needs to show information to the user and read values typed by the user.<br> These two actions are called Output and Input.<br><br> C uses two main functions:<br><br> printf → to display text or values<br> scanf → to read user input<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. Output: printf</b></font><br><br> printf is used to show messages or variable values on the screen.<br><br> Example:<br> printf("Hello!");<br><br> You can also display variables:<br><br> int age = 20;<br> printf("Age: %d", age);<br><br> %d is a format specifier meaning “display an integer”.<br><br> Common format specifiers:<br><br> %d → integer<br> %f → float<br> %c → character<br> %s → string<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Input: scanf</b></font><br><br> scanf reads a value typed by the user.<br><br> Example:<br><br> int age;<br> scanf("%d", &age);<br><br> Notice the & symbol.<br> It gives the memory address of the variable so C can store the value inside it.<br><br> More examples:<br><br> float price;<br> scanf("%f", &price);<br><br> char letter;<br> scanf("%c", &letter);<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Full Example Program</b></font><br><br> #include &lt;stdio.h&gt;<br><br> int main() {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;int age;<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Enter your age: ");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;scanf("%d", &age);<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("You are %d years old.", age);<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;return 0;<br> }<br><br> The program:<br><br> ✔ asks the user for their age<br> ✔ stores it<br> ✔ displays it<br><br> <font color="#008000"><b>Summary</b></font><br><br> printf → displays text or values<br> scanf → reads user input<br> Format specifiers tell C what type you are using (%d, %f, etc.)<br> & is required when reading values with scanf<br><br> These two functions make your program interactive.<br><br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours8">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 8: The FOR Loop (Repeat a Fixed Number of Times)</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is a Loop?</b></font><br> A loop repeats a set of instructions several times.<br> The FOR loop is used when we know exactly how many repetitions are needed.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. What Is a FOR Loop?</b></font><br> A FOR loop repeats steps from a starting number to an ending number.<br><br> Example:<br> “Repeat this exercise 10 times.”<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Structure (in natural language)</b></font><br> FOR i from start to end<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Do this action<br><br> Here, <b>i</b> is a counter that changes automatically at each step.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Examples</b></font><br> - FOR i from 1 to 5: WRITE i.<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;→ Displays 1, 2, 3, 4, 5<br><br> - FOR count from 0 to 10: increase score by 1.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Why Use FOR Loops?</b></font><br> FOR loops help:<br> - Repeat actions a fixed number of times<br> - Process lists or ranges<br> - Create repetitive calculations<br><br> They make algorithms cleaner, shorter, and easier to write.<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours8_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 8: IF / ELSE Conditions in C</b></font><br><br> Conditions allow your program to make decisions.<br> They let your code choose between different actions based on a value or situation.<br><br> Example decisions in real life:<br><br> If it is raining &rarr; take an umbrella<br> If you score above 50 &rarr; you pass<br> If the battery is low &rarr; show a warning<br><br> In C, you use if, else if, and else.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. The IF Statement</b></font><br><br> Used to check if a condition is true.<br><br> if (condition) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;// instructions<br> }<br><br> Example:<br><br> int age = 18;<br><br> if (age &gt;= 18) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Adult");<br> }<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. IF / ELSE</b></font><br><br> Use else when you want something to happen if the condition is false.<br><br> if (age &gt;= 18) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Adult");<br> } else {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Minor");<br> }<br><br> Only one of the two blocks will run.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. ELSE IF</b></font><br><br> Used when you need multiple conditions.<br><br> if (score &gt;= 90) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Excellent");<br> }<br> else if (score &gt;= 50) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Good");<br> }<br> else {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Fail");<br> }<br><br> The program checks conditions from top to bottom and executes the first true one.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Conditions Use Relational & Logical Operators</b></font><br><br> Examples of valid conditions:<br><br> if (x &gt; 0)<br> if (age &gt;= 18 &amp;&amp; age &lt;= 60)<br> if (letter == &apos;A&apos;)<br> if (score != 0)<br><br> You can combine operators:<br><br> == equal<br> != not equal<br> &gt; &lt; greater / less than<br> &gt;= &lt;= greater-or-equal / less-or-equal<br> &amp;&amp; AND<br> || OR<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Full Example Program</b></font><br><br> #include &lt;stdio.h&gt;<br><br> int main() {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;int number;<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Enter a number: ");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;scanf("%d", &number);<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;if (number &gt; 0) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Positive");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;}<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;else if (number &lt; 0) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Negative");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;}<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;else {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Zero");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;}<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;return 0;<br> }<br><br> <font color="#008000"><b>Summary</b></font><br><br> IF &rarr; check a condition<br> ELSE &rarr; run code when the condition is false<br> ELSE IF &rarr; test additional conditions<br> Conditions use relational and logical operators<br><br> IF/ELSE is one of the most important concepts in C programming.<br><br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours9">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 9: WHILE Loop (Repeat Until a Condition Becomes False)</b></font><br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. What Is a WHILE Loop?</b></font><br> A WHILE loop repeats a block of instructions as long as a condition is true.<br> The loop stops when the condition becomes false.<br><br> Real-life example:<br> “While the battery is above 10%, keep using the phone.”<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. How It Works</b></font><br> The algorithm:<br> - Checks the condition<br> - If the condition is true, it repeats the actions<br> - If the condition becomes false, the loop stops<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Structure (in natural language)</b></font><br> WHILE condition is true<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Do this action<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Examples</b></font><br> - “WHILE score &lt; 100, increase score by 10.”<br> - “WHILE temperature &gt; 0, decrease temperature by 1.”<br> The loop continues until the condition fails.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>5. Why Use WHILE Loops?</b></font><br> Use WHILE when:<br> - You don’t know in advance how many repetitions are needed<br> - The repetition depends on a condition<br> - You want the loop to stop automatically when the condition changes<br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="cours9_C">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000"><b>Course 9: SWITCH / CASE (Multiple Conditions in C)</b></font><br><br> The switch statement allows your program to choose between several possible actions based on the value of one variable.<br> It is very useful when you have many choices to test.<br><br> Instead of writing many if / else if, switch makes the code cleaner.<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>1. When to Use SWITCH</b></font><br><br> Use switch when:<br><br> - You check one variable<br> - You compare it to fixed values<br> - You need many different cases<br><br> Example situations:<br><br> Menu selections (1, 2, 3…)<br> Days of the week<br> Grades or levels<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>2. Basic Structure</b></font><br><br> switch (value) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;case X:<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;// instructions<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;break;<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;case Y:<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;// instructions<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;break;<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;default:<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;// instructions if no case matches<br> }<br><br> <b>value</b>: the variable you are checking<br> <b>case</b>: each possible value<br> <b>break</b>: stops the switch block<br> <b>default</b>: optional, runs when no case matches<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>3. Simple Example</b></font><br><br> int choice = 2;<br><br> switch (choice) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;case 1:<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Start");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;break;<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;case 2:<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Settings");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;break;<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;case 3:<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Exit");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;break;<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;default:<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Invalid option");<br> }<br><br> The output will be:<br><br> Settings<br><br> <font color="#800080"><b>4. Example with User Input</b></font><br><br> int day;<br> printf("Enter a day (1-3): ");<br> scanf("%d", &day);<br><br> switch (day) {<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;case 1:<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Monday");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;break;<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;case 2:<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Tuesday");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;break;<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;case 3:<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Wednesday");<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;break;<br><br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;default:<br> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;printf("Unknown day");<br> }<br><br> <font color="#008000"><b>Summary</b></font><br><br> SWITCH is used when one variable can take many values<br> Each CASE represents a possible value<br> BREAK prevents unwanted execution<br> DEFAULT is used when no case matches<br><br> Switch makes programs with many choices clearer and easier to read.<br><br> ]]>
</string>
    <string name="intro">
<![CDATA[ <font color="#FF0000">Welcome to Code Flow! </font><br><br> You are about to embark on an amazing journey into the world of programming!<br><br> Here, you will learn algorithmics and the C language step by step, at your own pace, in a clear and interactive way.<br><br> Each lesson is designed to teach you essential concepts, and each quiz will allow you to test your skills and challenge yourself.<br><br> Don’t worry if it seems difficult at first: every line of code you write makes you stronger, more confident, and closer to your goals.<br><br> So take on challenges, experiment, make mistakes, and try again — that’s how you become a real programmer! <br><br> <font color="#800080">Ready to turn your ideas into reality? <b>Let’s code and shape your future right now!</b></font> ]]>
</string>
    <style name="Base.Theme.ProjetM2" parent="Theme.Material3.DayNight.NoActionBar">
        
        
    </style>
    <style name="Theme.ProjetM2" parent="Base.Theme.ProjetM2"/>
</resources>